Hi, welcome back! I can imagine that the last video left you a little bit
嗨，欢迎回来！ 我可以想像 最后一个视频让你有些困惑，
confused, because
因为
I was doing some magic here, just clicking fields together and suddenly
我在这变了个魔术，只要一起点击字段，
everything worked.
突然一切都解決了。
Maybe you were screaming at your computer screen again, like what's going on
也许你正在你的电脑屏幕前再次大叫，
here?
这是怎么回事？
So in this video we're really going to look at what
所以，在这个视频中，我们将仔细地探讨
exactly happened there. So
那究竟是怎么一回事。 所以
we're not going to work with adding a new pivot table anymore.
我们不会在 添加新的数据透视表了。
Actually, secretly, you didn't know that, but secretly
事实上，暗地里你并不知道，
we were working with power-pivot so let's go to the PowerPivot worksheet and
我们正在使用power-pivot，所以 让我们用PowerPivot 工作表
manage our data.
管理我们的数据吧。
And what you see here, is that PowerPivot has stored all that
你在这里看到的，
data for us. The data that we have added to the data model, it's
是PowerPivot 帮我们储存所有的数据。 我们添加到数据模型的数据，
a little bit tricky actually it should have said
有点棘手，实际上它应该是说
add this data to a PowerPivot model. Because PowerPivot is storing that data for us.
添加此数据到PowerPivot模型中。 因为PowerPivot为我们储存那些数据。
And here you see the data in a diagram view and if I click that link
你在这里看到图表中的数据 ，如果我点击这个链接
you see that this is the link that I have actually created
你会了解这个连结是我在点击时所实际创造的
when I was clicking. I said this is related to that
我说这与该啤酒有关
beer is related to the name. So let's improve those names a little because range
与名称有关。 因此，让我们稍微改善这些名字 因为range
and range1 aren't good names. Let's rename them to register and beer
和range1都不是好名字。 让我们 把他们重新命名为登记和啤酒
so they align with what is in our spreadsheet model.
以便让他们与我们的 电子表格模型是一致的。
So
所以
now we have a view of our data, this allows us to do some more cool analysis.
现在，我们能够看到我们的数据，这让我们可以做一些更酷的分析。
For instance,
例如，
we would like to know: What countries do the beers that are popular in our bar
我们想知道：我们的酒吧里最受欢迎的啤酒
stem from?
起源于那些国家？
So do we drink US beers? Do we drink
那么我们喝的是美国啤酒？ 还是
German beers? Dutch beers maybe? We want to know that.
德国啤酒？ 又或许是荷兰啤酒？ 我们希望 知道这一点。
But in order to do that we need to have some more information.
但为了做到这一点，我们需要更多的信息。
We need to go to the brewery worksheet, because the brewery worksheet has the
我们需要参考啤酒厂工作表 ， 因为啤酒厂工作表里有
information of what
那些
brewery is in what country. So we're not going to make another pivot table, we
啤酒厂是来自哪个国家的信息。 所以我们不 必再制作另一个数据透视表，我们
don't need to do that to add it to the data model.
不需要为了将其添加到 数据模型而这么做。
You know that we were secretly working with PowerPivot, so we can say now
你知道我们正偷偷地使用PowerPivot，所以我们现在可以说，
I want to
我想要
go to the PowerPivot ribbon and add
进入PowerPivot的功能区，并直接添加
the data to the data model directly. So you see here
数据到数据模型。 所以你在这里看到
we get all the data in a similar way that we got it before
我们用了之前类似的方式得到所有数据
all the column headers are right there. We can immediately rename it to
所有的行标题都在那里。 我们可以立即将其重命名为
breweries
啤酒厂
and now we can create a relation. We don't need to go to the
而且现在我们可以建立一个关联。 我们 不需要进入数据透视表，
pivot table where Excel says: Ha,
表中Excel会说：哈，
I need a relation then we create it, we create it directly.
我需要一个关联，然后我才可以建立它， 我们直接创建它。
We can say the brewery name in the beer worksheet is related to the name
我们可以说，啤酒工作表的啤酒厂名字与
column in the brewery worksheet. And when we make that relation
与啤酒厂工作表的名字行有关联 。 而当我们建立这样的关联
we can use that to build our pivot tables on. So if you go to a pivot table
我们可以用它来扩建我们的数据透视表。 所以，如果你进入数据透视表
now, you see that in addition to to register and the beers
现在，你可以看到，除了 注册和啤酒资料以外，
we also have a list of breweries. And we can use that
我们还有啤酒厂的列表。 我们 可以使用这些
to make our country analysis, we can drag country in
来进行关于国家的分析，我们可以 拖入国家信息，
and then we get the number of beers that we have sold
然后我们便能得到我们已经售出的啤酒的数量
for each of the countries. So what happens in the background is this
对应其中的每一个国家。 所以, 在后台中将会发生这样的情况
country is linked to the beers trough the brewery name and those beers are linked to
"国家"经由"啤酒厂名称"与"啤酒"相连, 而这些啤酒则与...连接
the beer list, to the register log
啤酒列表，与注册日志
in the beer name. So PowerPivot traverses all those relations
在啤酒名称中。 所以, PowerPivot遍历所有 这些关系
secretly in the background, makes something like a VLOOKUP
暗中在后台运行，使它像VLOOKUP
to haul all the data in and then you can build a pivot table
把所有数据拉进来，然后你可以就在它上头建立一个数据透视表
right on top of it. We don't need to do the actual VLOOKUP,
我们不需要真的使用VLOOKUP，
if we add everything to the data model and create the relations
如果我们添加所有东西到数据模型并创建关联
we can build a pivot table on top of that. So let's look at the data again,
我们可以在此之上建立一个数据透视表。 那么,让我们再来看看这些数据，
what is the traversal that we go through? We go from the register log
我们查看的是什么遍历？ 我们从注册列表
via the name through the brewery from the brewery name through brewery
通过"名字"查看啤酒厂 通过"啤酒厂名字"查看啤酒厂资料
and then through the country. So that's the exact same traversal
然后通过"国家"。 所以这与我所经历的遍历完全一样，
that I did, but now I did it in the data instead of in the data model.
但现在我在数据內使用而不是数据模型。
So that leaves us with this pivot table
所以这给我们留下了数据透视表 ，
in which we can see what are the beers that we have sold
在表中我们可以看到每个国家所卖的啤酒是什么。